Guide to the Elizabeth Hislop Scrapbook
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elizabeth Hislop scrapbook
1905-1908
SC0752
Hislop, Elizabeth
2.5 Linear feet
Scrapbook documents her student life at Stanford and includes student forms, notes, calling cards, dance cards, programs, postcards, photographs, and a 1905 Stanford songbook. Many pages are annotated; of note are items pertaining to the 1906 earthquake, including the student relief pass card of Preston Brady Delano.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Elizabeth Hislop earned an A.B. in English at Stanford University in 1908; she was a member of the Delta Gamma sorority.
Description of the Collection
Scrapbook documents her student life at Stanford and includes student forms, notes, calling cards, dance cards, programs, postcards, photographs, and a 1905 Stanford songbook. Many pages are annotated; of note are items pertaining to the 1906 earthquake, including the student relief pass card of Preston Brady Delano.
Arrangement
Due to its fragile nature, the volume was unbound and the pages put into folders.
Access Terms
Hislop, Elizabeth; Earthquakes --California --San Francisco.; Scrapbooks
Collection Contents
- Scrapbook
  - Page 1 – photo of Delta Gamma house (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Page 2 – photo of Bess (?) in garden with note, possibly from sorority sisters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Page 3 – train stubs, class schedule, list of Alpha Phi events (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Page 4 – Stanford Football Songs, 1905 edition (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Page 5-6 – calling cards, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Page 7-8 – place cards from dinners / small Stanford pennant (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Page 9-10 – invitation to Delta Gamma dance and dance card, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Page 11-12 – note from Julia H. Gulliver (Rockford College) and a poem about Bessie, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Page 13-14 – party favors from Japanese dinner at Alpha Phi house (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Page 15-16 – letter from Frances Hall (Chicago) urging her to pledge Delta Gamma, 1905 / place cards (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Page 17-18 – place card from a breakfast and program from a sorority Field Day in San Mateo, 1905 / postcard of Hotel St. Francis, S.F. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Page 19-20 – mementos from stay at Hotel St. Francis (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Page 21-22 - mementos from colonial dinner and dance at the Delta Gamma house (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Page 23-24 – note from Edna B. [Brown] and leather football favor from dinner at Delta Gamma house (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Page 25-26 – favors from Delta Gamma events / calling cards (male visitors from Berkeley) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Page 27 – invitation to join the Delta Gamma sorority (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Page 28 – Wilson's menu and annotation (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Page 29-30 – sorority note / photograph of unidentified woman (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Page 31-32 – mementos from Delta Gamma initiation, Oct. 1905 / images of a college not Stanford (possibly Berkeley) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Page 33 – invitation and dance card (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Page 34 – letter from Adela [Wohler?], Rockford College, thanking her for her work as class president at Rockford (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Page 35-36 – dance cards / red ribbon (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Page 37 – program from "The Beauty Shop," the annual football show, November 1905 [page 38 was blank] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Page 39-40 – dance card and favor from football dinner, November 1905 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Page 41-42 – party mementos / favor from Thanksgiving dinner at ΔΚΕ house (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Page 43-44 – dance card from Junior Prom at Berkeley, menu from Tait's / printed image of oak trees (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Page 45-46 – Musical Program at Tait's, night after the prom, November 1905 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Page 47-48 – Menu from Geo. Haas & Sons, livery card, and notes re ride through the park in S.F. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Page 49-50 – program from "The College Widow," S.F. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Page 51-52 – 2 comical notes from "Christmas Night at the Bachelor Profs" / Wilson's menu with annotation regarding a date (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Page 53-54 – postcard from Pauline and Mt. Tamalpais Railway schedule, page annotated / journal entries for Dec. 26 [1905] to Jan. 22 [1906], page annotated "I decide to keep 'a-line-a-day' book" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Page 55-56 – dance card from Phi Delt dance, Jan. 4, 1906 / postcard of Memorial Church interior, page annotated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Page 57-58 – hand-painted card with 1906 calendar (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Page 59-60 – registration card, telegram from home (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Page 61-62 – sorority items January 1906 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Page 63 – invitation to Chi Psi dance, letter regarding start of an alumnae chapter of Chi Theta Psi at Rockford College (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Page 64 – acceptance note (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Page 65-66 – dance card, Delta Gamma freshmen party (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Page 67-68 – marriage announcement for Clara Louise Hagar and James Roscoe Tallman, January 1906 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Page 69-70 – Chi Psi dance card (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Page 71-72 – Valentine card, dinner place card (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Page 73-74 – note from Bess, Valentine card, invitation (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Page 75-76 – Valentine note, Encina Club invitation / program from "She Stoops to Conquer," Sophomore Comedy (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Page 77-78 – telegram re visit, postcard from University of Chicago Mar. 1906 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Page 79-80 – dance card from Encina Club At Home, Feb. 23, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Page 81-82 – Madrona reception, place card from Delta Tau dinner dance, annotated "Three men for each girl so we are all popular. Fine!" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Page 83-84 – Program, Delta Gamma reunion March 17, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Page 85-86 – Postcard from Niagara Falls, receipt for syllabus with annotation (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Page 87-88 – mementos from Delta Gamma receptions / ticket for baseball game Mar. 28th (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Page 89-90 – Junior Opera program "Stanford the Life Strenuous" with annotation re sprained ankle (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Page 91-92 – dance card from Junior Prom, Mar. 30, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Page 93-94 – Annotated "I spend ten days in the hospital" with 2 notes from friends, April 1906 [the Guild Hospital] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Page 95-96 – two notes while in Hospital (one from George Spurrier) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Page 97-98 – card that came with flowers from Mrs. Delano, and a note from Alice (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Page 99-100 – two notes from friends while in hospital / photo of earthquake damage to Memorial Church and calling card of Ralph Bandini (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Page 101-102 – "The Earthquake!" telegraph from family April 18, 1906, and letter from friend in Los Angeles (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Page 103-104 – invitation to come to Los Angeles, photo of damage to new gymnasium (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Page 105-106 – student relief pass-card issued to P.B. Delano / letter from Genevieve (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Page 107-108 – annotated "Train Letters" with two notes (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Page 109-110 – certificate that Miss Elizabeth Hislop is a Stanford student en route home, page annotated with names of companions on trip (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Page 111-112 – photograph of Fred with 2 women, newsprint programs for 2 plays / programs for 2 plays (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Page 113-114 – newsprint programs for 2 plays / menu (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Page 115-116 – program from installation of Delta Gamma at Illinois (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Page 117 – scorecard for baseball game between Illinois and Michigan (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Page 118 – Delta Gamma dance card (not Stanford) and place card from banquet at Rockford College (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Page 119-120 – clipping re Edna Brown's fall from bluff (Rockford, Ill.) and 2 photographs of Rockford friends / programs from 2 plays (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Page 121-122 – manuscript poem by F. F. Briggs / invitation to Roble Club At Home and two notes (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Page 123-124 – program for Class of 1906 play, dance card from '06 commencement dance, photo of "The Snark" on horseback / exam from Greek 10, program from a play (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Page 125-126 – three acceptance notes for Delta Gamma events / Encina Club At Home invitation, two musical programs, birthday letter from her Uncle Herman, October 1906 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Page 127-128 – invitations, page annotated / Senior Circus item and dance card (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Page 129-130 – acceptance note from Preston Delano, place card from Thanksgiving dinner, November 1906 / cartoon by a friend and a dance card (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Page 131-132 – dance cards / postcard and several calling cards (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Page 133-134 – Encina Club dance card Jan. 26, 1907 / dance card (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Page 135-136 – dance card / Delta Gamma dance card, Feb. 16, 1907, two invitations (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Page 137 – dance card, Field Day ticket, Delta Gamma reunion favor [use photocopy], program for "A Stunt Roble Gym March 7, 1907" [use photocopy] (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Page 138 – Junior Day program March 22, 1907, sorority favor (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Page 139 – telegram, program from "You Never Can Tell" Sophomore Comedy, March 1907, dance card (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Page 140 – program from "Stanford the Life Strenuous" Junior Opera, Delta Gamma examination 1907 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Page 141-142 – concert program, score sheet from freshman track meet / annotations but no items on second page (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Page 143 – postcard from a cousin, concert program, place card from senior banquet May 11, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Page 144 – Senior Week Program, May 16-22, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Page 145-146 – dance cards 1907 / registration card for second semester of 1906/07, crepe paper pennant, photograph (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Page 147-148 – annotated "Back at Stanford – Senior Rushing begins" with photograph of people at railroad car and assorted sorority notes / dance card, note from D. S. Jordan requesting representative of Delta Gamma for the President's Conference, Sept. 13, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Page 149-150 – dance card, invitation, clipping on death of Mrs. Lemon, pioneer / annotated "I am put out of the Lemon Club" with note announcing same, receipt, party favor (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Page 151-152 – Delta Gamma items / invitation and place cards (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Page 153-154 – invitation / invitation and dance card (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Page 155-156 – dance card from Sophomore Cotillion, Dec. 7, 1907 / receipt, several dance cards (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Page 157 – 3 dance cards, 1 calling card (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Page 158 – dance card, letter from Gail, typed letter from Genevieve, Feb. 11, 1908 [use photocopy] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Page 159-160 – Delta Gamma initiation item, invitation / 2 dance cards (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Page 161 – dance cards, calling cards (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Page 162 – Program from "The Manoeuvres of Jane" Feb. 15, 1908, dance card (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Page 163-164 – postcard, invitation / dance card, invitation (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Page 165-166 – program from Junior Opera "Butterfly Isle" March 26, 1908, program from "The Fleecers" (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Page 167 – comic letter with clipping, small Stanford pennant (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Page 168 – delivery tag from pharmacy, memorabilia re "Egyptian Princess" May 1, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Page 169-170 – at home card of Mr. and Mrs. Jordan, Delta Gamma program, fragment of a comic note [use photocopy] / photograph of Hislop home in Chicago, place card (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Page 171-172 – photograph of "Edna Brown's wedding party Rockford" and photograph of unidentified house (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Loose items 1906-1908: fragment of letter written 5/5/06, invitation letter to join Delta Gamma, two invitations 1908 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Original front cover (Box 5, Folder 22)